A Guide to the Venable and Southall Family Photographs
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10100-d
Venable and Southall Family Photographs 1867?-1896
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10100-d
44 items
Julius Barclay
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These photographs were given to the Library on September 10, 1990, by Mr. Julius Barclay of Charlottesville, Virginia, without restrictions.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of forty-four nineteenth century photographs, the majority in a carte de viste style, of the Southall, Minor, and Venable families of Charlottesville, Virginia, including two Afro-American family servants.
Container List
The numbered photographs were removed from two photograph albums and include the following people
- 1) "Mammy" Hattie and Lucy Landon Minor(5 1\2 months old), 1893 Feb
- 2) Charles Scott Venable, 187-?
- 3) Charles Scott Venable, 1877 Christmas
- 4) Charles [Scott Venable](London), 1894
- 5) Charles Scott Venable(19 years old), 1896
- 6) [ Madge Bonney Venable?], n.d.
- 7) Elizabeth L. Southall, 1868
- 8) W. Abbot Southall, n.d.
- 9) J[ames] Powell Cocke Southall, n.d.
- 10) Evelyn M. Southall, n.d.
- 11) Mary Stuart Southall, n.d.
- 12) Martha Cocke Southall, n.d.
- 13) [ J. Thompson Brown?] (son of N.P. Brown), n.d.
- 15) Mary James, [1867 ?]
- 30) William Southall, n.d.
- 31) Colonel [?] in Confederate uniform, n.d.
- 32) [ Charles Sharp?], n.d.
- 33) Lucy S[outhall] Sharp, n.d.
- 34) Fanny R. Milledge, n.d.
- 35) Charles Scott Venable(16 months old), 187-?
- 36) Charles Scott Venable(infant), 187-?
- 37) Mrs. Peter C. Minor(cousin [Lucy ?]), n.d.
- 38) Peter C. Minor, n.d.
- 39) Mrs. [Peronneau ?] Brown, n.d.
- 40) Stephen Osborne Southall, n.d.
- 41) Stephen Osborne Southall, n.d.
- 42) [Dr.?] Nelson, n.d.
- 43) Mrs. Hewett & Joe [Allen ?] Hewett, n.d.
- 44) the Reverend [Bowman ?]
- 45) Mrs. [Bowman ?], n.d.
- 46) Uncle Joe [Stras], n.d.
- 47) Aunt Emily [Stras], n.d.
- 48) Mrs. James [Souther?], n.d.
- 49) Jennie Sharp Ambler, n.d.
- 50) Eliza Howard, n.d.
- 51) Mrs. Isaac Coles[Enniscorthy, Great Britain ?], n.d.
- 52) Mrs. Willie Timberlake, n.d.
- 53) Natalie [?], n.d.
- 54) Lady Montgomery, n.d.
- 55) Mrs. Richard Haldeun(Edinburgh, Scotland)
- 56) Miss Maud Warwick(Dublin, Ireland)
- 57) "Mammy" Sally Cole, n.d.
- 58) Washington and Lee University student